<Document>
#  Rule B1: Play a Realistic Character

  You must roleplay a character that is believable and acts as if they are in the setting they exist in.  Your character's actions, feelings and knowledge should be solely those of your character, and not your own as a player.

  - Act in character throughout the round, and focus on collaborating with others to advance the story.  Whether you do something should be based on whether or not it makes sense for your character to do such.
  - Do not play a ‘master of everything’ character.  Collaborate with other players, ask for assistance and negotiate as needed.  It makes the world feel larger when you work together.
  - Actions that have no regard for your character's health and safety aren’t acceptable.  For example, act to threats made as if they are legitimate threats, don’t jump into space for a few moments just because a medbed will fix you up.  Roleplaying insanity or mental illness as an excuse to bypass this is not allowed, nor is roleplaying suicide.
  - Do not annoy other players without any roleplay or IC reason to be doing so.

  ## Rule B1.1: Following naming conventions
  - In-character names must not make obvious references nor be a play on words, and must not be obscene.
  - Do not name yourself after another players character, do not attempt to impersonate anyone.
  - All species have a naming convention, try to follow them where able.
  - Ships follow the same naming conventions, although you have greater freedom with making references and plays on words.
  - If you want to have a name that you think may not be allowed, ask an admin for clarification and they can confirm if it’s fine!

  ## Rule B1.2: Communicate in Character
  - Communicate as your character would, and use the emotes channels to describe your character’s physical movements.  This allows using the emotes channels for talking in such manners as writing in books, typing into your PDA or otherwise.
  - Avoid use of Netspeak, such that it might break immersion.
  - Do not engage in meta-communications (via Discord, OOC or other third party software) if said communication is to gain an advantage.

  ## Rule B1.3: New life rules
  Sometimes people will die, these rules aid in Outlaws not being immediately unveiled if they are attempting to keep themselves a secret.
  - If you are revived within the round, your character will struggle to remember anything beyond vague elements.  “They had a laser sword” or “A large person was shooting at me”.  This includes not naming your killer directly.
  - If you join the round again with the same character, they are a ‘duplicate’ of your character, with no memories of what the other character got up to during their shift.  This means you cannot recover previous assets or find it without sufficient roleplay reason.

  ## Rule B1.4: Escalate appropriately
  Have an in character justification for your actions and attacking others, the priority of the server is to roleplay and tell a story.  The level of escalation is allowed proportionate to the level of roleplay invested.  Although this will depend upon the situation, killing vermin on your ship needs no more justification than “it was vermin on my ship.”
  - Escalate a situation appropriate as your character would, keeping in mind that space is a dangerous place and killing anyone should be a last resort.
  - Do not attack another player without a legitimate, explainable roleplay reason that could be applied in a similar, real-life scenario.
  - If a fight results in someone being critically injured, support and aid medical ships in getting to them and having them revived.  If they do die, destroying or hiding the body is a bannable offence.

  </Document>
