<Document>
# Rule C2: Outlaw Rules

  Being an antagonist does not allow you to stop playing a character.  Whilst engaging in this activity, you should seek to make shifts more engaging and fun, as you will be an initiator of ‘drama’ and ‘disequilibrium’ in a round.  Success as an Outlaw is not measured in financial or combat success, but in aiding in telling the most interesting story for everyone.


  - Outlaws are free of set objectives, and can perform damage and activities to achieve their own goals they have set.  Damage must be minimal and proportional, although through roleplay damage becomes more proportional.  Example: Holding a gun to someone's face as a hostage to get everyone to pay you is acceptable, shooting everyone dead to go through their wallets is not acceptable.
  - Killing players without prior roleplay or justified reasons to is to be avoided in all possible ways.  People who do not make an attempt at self-preservation or initiate on you are exempt from this.
  - You should not be killing people in such a way that will result in their body being unrecoverable.
  - Whilst you are not expected to act antagonistic at all times, it is still encouraged to act as an antagonist throughout the round whilst roleplaying.  If your intentions aren’t to play an antagonist, play a role that isn’t an Outlaw, failure to do such may result in dewhitelisting.
  - Other outlaws are not necessarily your friends.  There may be honour amongst thieves, but they are not defaulting to your allies.  You can betray other Outlaws, but you cannot betray Perdition.
  - You are required to have a good understanding of Outlaw CoH or to be in the process of learning it.  If you violate or fail to follow these documents, it is appropriate so long as you are making an effort to roleplay the consequences of these actions and still acting in ‘good faith’ for storytelling purposes.
  - Do not excessively take from players that you are stealing from in the below manners;
  -- Do not engage in interactions that include stealing from someone's bank accounts
  -- If a player surrenders, keep plundering to a reasonable level such as not to ruin the player's round.
  -- If they fight back and you succeed, you are free to loot as you wish, but do not loot the ship in such a manner as to remove its ability to sustain life or fly.
  --We understand that during combat systems / walls can get damaged, you do not need to repair this, but leave enough materials they can repair their ship.
  - If you are concerned that anything you’re about to do is may not be allowed, please aHelp and ask for clarification.

</Document>
